Register of the Trotsky collection, 1917-1995
Hoover Institution Archives
Leon Trotsky Collection
1917-1995
92032
Hoover Institution Archives
47 manuscript boxes, 4 envelopes, 2 phonorecords, 1 framed painting (20.2 linear feet)
Writings and correspondence of the Russian revolutionary leader Leon Trotsky, including drafts of articles and books, correspondence with John G. Wright and other leaders of the Socialist Workers Party of the United States, and typed copies of correspondence with V. I. Lenin; correspondence and reports of secretaries of Trotsky and leaders of the Socialist Workers Party, relating especially to efforts to safeguard Trotsky and to his assassination; records of the American Committee for the Defense of Leon Trotsky and of the Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trials; correspondence and writings of Nataliia Sedova Trotskaia and of Lev Sedov; and published and unpublished material relating to Trotsky. Assembled from records of the Socialist Workers Party and from papers of Wright and other party leaders. Also includes detailed summaries of correspondence in the Trotsky Papers at Harvard University. Boxes 1-45 also available on microfilm (50 reels). Phonotape cassette dub of sound recordings also available.
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
The Hoover Institution Archives acquired the Leon Trotsky Collection from the Anchor Foundation in 1992. A register to the collection was prepared that year and remains the principal overall description of and finding aid to the collection. Material subsequently received from the Anchor Foundation was described in the Addendum in 2016.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternate Forms Available
Boxes 1-45 available on microfilm (50 reels). Phonotape cassette dub of sound recordings also available.
Historical Note
The Leon Trotsky Collection of material by and about the Russian revolutionary Leon Trotsky (1879-1940) was assembled by the Socialist Workers Party and its affiliate, the Library of Social History. Originating as the Communist League of America in 1928, the Socialist Workers Party adopted its present name and form of existence in 1938. As the American section of the Fourth International movement led by Trotsky, it maintained close contact with him, especially during the period of his exile in Mexico, from January 1937 until his assassination in August 1940. The collection was housed in the Library of Social History in New York City until it was acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1992.
The major sources of material in the collection are central files of the Socialist Workers Party, and papers of individual leaders of the party, most notably John G. Wright, but also James P. Cannon, Farrell Dobbs, Albert Goldman, Joseph Hansen, and others. There are, in a few instances, photocopies of documents from the Harvard University Library, the Internationaal Instituut voor Sociale Geschiedenis, and other archival repositories.
The collection includes original manuscripts of writings by Trotsky--notably portions of Vie de Lenine: Jeunesse, Les Crimes de Staline, and Stalin--as well as typed copies and rare printed copies. Original manuscripts and many typed copies are from the papers of John G. Wright, the principal translator during Trotsky's lifetime of English language editions of his works.
The collection also includes many original letters from Trotsky to leaders of the Socialist Workers Party, as well as carbons of their replies, and originals, carbons and typed copies of Trotsky's correspondence with others. Of particular note in the collection is one of three existing sets of typed copies of correspondence between Trotsky and V. I. Lenin, prepared from Soviet archival sources at Trotsky's direction.
Originals and copies of letters and writings of Trotsky's wife Nataliia Sedova Trotskaia, and of his son Lev Sedov, are distinct parts of the collection.
Correspondence between Socialist Workers Party leaders in New York and secretaries and guards of Trotsky in Mexico (many of them members of the party) form a significant part of the collection, as do Socialist Workers Party records relating to the Dewey Commission hearings of 1937 on the charges made against Trotsky in the Moscow Trials; the investigation of Trotsky's assassination; the disposition of his archives; and posthumous publication of his biography Stalin.
The collection also contains selected published and unpublished materials about Trotsky collected by the Socialist Workers Party and the Library of Social History up until 1980; and survey sheets prepared by a Socialist Workers Party/Library of Social History team inventorying correspondence in the Exile Papers section of the Trotsky Papers in the Harvard University Library.
Audiovisual materials include photographs of the Coyoacan household from the papers of Evelyn Reed and George Novack; and a sound recording of a speech by Trotsky.
Scope and Contents note
Writings and correspondence of the Russian revolutionary leader Leon Trotsky, including drafts of articles and books, correspondence with John G. Wright and other leaders of the Socialist Workers Party of the United States, and typed copies of correspondence with V. I. Lenin; correspondence and reports of secretaries of Trotsky and leaders of the Socialist Workers Party, relating especially to efforts to safeguard Trotsky and to his assassination; records of the American Committee for the Defense of Leon Trotsky and of the Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trials; correspondence and writings of Nataliia Sedova Trotskaia and of Lev Sedov; and published and unpublished material relating to Trotsky. Assembled from records of the Socialist Workers Party and from papers of Wright and other party leaders. Also includes detailed summaries of correspondence in the Trotsky Papers at Harvard University.
Boxes 1-45 also available on microfilm (50 reels). Phonotape cassette dub of sound recordings also available.
The Addendum includes United States government documents detailing surveillance of Leon Trotsky in exile (photocopies obtained from government archives); bibliographies of writings by Trotsky and of internal bulletins of the Fourth International movement during his lifetime; and a subject file of assorted correspondence, memoranda and printed matter relating to Trotsky and Trotskyism. Also included is a portrait painting of Natalia Sedova Trotsky.
American Committee for the Defense of Leon Trotsky.; Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made Against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trials.; Fourth International.; Lenin, Vladimir Il'ich, 1870-1924.; Sedov, Lev, 1906-1938.; Socialist Workers Party.; Trotskaia, Nataliia Ivanovna, 1882-1962.; Trotsky, Leon, 1879-1940.; Wright, John G., 1902-1956.; Audiotapes.; Communism.; Mexico.; Moscow Trials, Moscow, Russia, 1936-1937.; Phonorecords.; Russia (Federation); Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Soviet Union--Politics and government--1917-1936.; Soviet Union.; United States--Politics and government.
- V. I. LENIN FILE, 1917-1924 (Box 1-9)
  Scope and Contents note
  Typed copies of documents in Soviet archives, consisting largely, but not exclusively, of correspondence between Leon Trotsky and V. I. Lenin, and of each with third parties, during the Russian Civil War and subsequent period up to the death of Lenin. Three sets of copies were made under the direction of Trotsky between 1925 and 1927. The other two sets are in the Harvard University Library and the Internationaal Instituut voor Sociale Geschiedenis, Amsterdam, respectively. Published versions of most of the documents appear in Jan M. Meier, ed., The Trotsky Papers, 1917-1922, 2 vols. (The Hague, 1964, 1971). Arranged by physical form.
  - Correspondence
    - Leon Trotsky to V. I. Lenin
      - 1918
        - January 31 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - August 6 (Folder 2)
        - (ca.), August 7-9 (Folder 3)
        - August 9 (Folder 4)
        - August 12 (Folder 5)
        - August 13 (Folder 6)
        - August 14 (Folder 7)
        - August 15 (Folder 8)
        - August 17 (Folder 9)
        - August 21 (Folder 10-11)
        - August 23 (Folder 12-13)
        - (ca.), August 23-31 (Folder 14)
        - August 24 (Folder 15)
        - August 25 (Folder 16)
        - August 27 (Folder 17)
        - August 28 (Folder 18)
        - August 29 (Folder 19)
        - September 11 (Folder 20)
        - September 14 (Folder 21)
        - September 26 (Folder 22-23)
        - November 7 (Folder 24)
        - November 25 (Folder 25-26)
        - November 29 (Folder 27-28)
        - December 1 (Folder 29-30)
        - December 14 (Folder 31-32)
        - December 26 (Folder 33-35)
        - December 27 (Folder 36-37)
        - December 28 (Folder 38)
        - December 29 (Folder 39)
        - December 30 (Folder 40)
        - December 31 (Folder 41-42)
      - 1919
        - January 2 (Folder 43-45)
        - January 3 (Folder 46)
        - January 7 (Folder 47)
        - (ca.), January 9-31 (Folder 48)
        - January 11 (Folder 49)
        - January 19 (Folder 50)
        - January 22 (Folder 51)
        - January 23 (Folder 52)
        - January 25 (Folder 53)
        - March 17 (Folder 54)
        - March 18 (Folder 55)
        - March 20 (Folder 56)
        - March 21 (Folder 57)
        - March 24 (Folder 58)
        - March 25 (Folder 59)
        - April 7 (Folder 60-61)
        - April 10 (Folder 62)
        - April 15 (Folder 63)
        - April 16 (Folder 64)
        - May 2 (Folder 65-66)
        - May 7 (Folder 67)
        - May 12 (Folder 68)
        - May 14 (Folder 69)
        - May 17 (Folder 70)
        - May 21 (Folder 71-74)
        - May 22 (Folder 75-77)
        - May 26 (Folder 78)
        - May 27 (Folder 79-80)
        - June 1 (Folder 81)
        - June 3 (Folder 82)
        - June 5 (Folder 83)
        - July 27 (Folder 84-85)
        - August 1 (Folder 86)
        - August 2 (Folder 87)
        - August 6 (Folder 88-90)
        - August 7 (Folder 91)
        - August 9 (Folder 92)
        - September 4 (Folder 93)
        - October 17 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        - October 19 (Folder 2)
        - October 20 (Folder 3-4)
        - October 24 (Folder 5)
        - October 25 (Folder 6-7)
        - October 27 (Folder 8)
        - October 30 (Folder 9)
        - November 2 (Folder 10)
        - November 3 (Folder 11)
        - December 22 (Folder 12)
      - 1920
        - January 26 (Folder 13)
        - February 11 (Folder 14)
        - February 16 (Folder 15-16)
        - February 19 (Folder 17-19)
        - February 26 (Folder 20)
        - February 27 (Folder 21)
        - February 28 (Folder 22)
        - March 2 (Folder 23)
        - March 4 (Folder 24)
        - March 5 (Folder 25)
        - March 8 (Folder 26-27)
        - March 9 (Folder 28-29)
        - March 12 (Folder 30)
        - March 20 (Folder 31)
        - March 24 (Folder 32)
        - March 26 (Folder 33)
        - April 20 (Folder 34)
        - April 26 (Folder 35)
        - April 30 (Folder 36)
        - May 1 (Folder 37)
        - May 2 (Folder 38)
        - May 7 (Folder 39)
        - May 21 (Folder 40)
        - June 3 (Folder 41)
        - June 4 (Folder 42)
        - June 5 (Folder 43)
        - July 13 (Folder 44-45)
        - August 2 (Folder 46)
        - August 4 (Folder 47-48)
        - August 13 (Folder 49)
        - August 15 (Folder 50)
        - August 17 (Folder 51-52)
        - August 18 (Folder 53)
        - August 31 (Folder 54)
        - September 12 (Folder 55)
        - September 13 (Folder 56)
        - September 24 (Folder 57)
        - October 1 (Folder 58)
        - October 2 (Folder 59)
        - October 10 (Folder 60)
        - October 16 (Folder 61)
        - October 25 (Folder 62)
        - November 1 (Folder 63)
        - November 19 (Folder 64-65)
        - November 25 (Folder 66)
        - November 27 (Folder 67)
      - 1921
        - March 15 (Folder 68)
        - May 3 (Folder 69)
        - June 5 (Folder 70)
        - July 3 (Folder 71-72)
        - August 1 (Folder 73)
        - August 2 (Folder 74)
        - August 15 (Folder 75)
        - August 25 (Folder 76)
        - September 21 (Folder 77)
        - October 10 (Folder 78-79)
        - October 11 (Folder 80)
        - November 14 (Folder 81)
        - November 23 (Folder 82)
        - December 16 (Folder 83)
        - December 20 (Folder 84)
      - 1922
        - January 21 (Folder 85)
        - January 30 (Folder 86)
        - April 5 (Folder 87)
        - December 12 (Folder 88)
        - December 13 (Folder 89)
    - V. I. Lenin to Leon Trotsky
      - 1918
        - February 7 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        - February 24 (Folder 2)
        - April 21 (Folder 3)
        - April 22 (Folder 4)
        - July 8 (Folder 5)
        - July 27 (Folder 6)
        - August 17 (Folder 7)
        - (ca.), August 18-21 (Folder 8)
        - August 19 (Folder 9)
        - August 21 (Folder 10-11)
        - August 22 (Folder 12)
        - August 30 (Folder 13)
        - September 7 (Folder 14)
        - September 12 (Folder 15)
        - November 3 (Folder 16)
        - November 5 (Folder 17)
        - November 7 (Folder 18)
        - November 19 (Folder 19)
        - December 13 (Folder 20)
      - 1919
        - January 3 (Folder 21)
        - January 24 (Folder 22)
        - January 27 (Folder 23)
        - May 14 (Folder 24)
        - May 15 (Folder 25)
        - May 18 (Folder 26)
        - May 21 (Folder 27)
        - May 22 (Folder 28-29)
        - May 23 (Folder 30)
        - May 30 (Folder 31-32)
        - June 2 (Folder 33-34)
        - June 3 (Folder 35)
        - June 4 (Folder 36)
        - June 5 (Folder 37)
        - June 6 (Folder 38)
        - July 8 (Folder 39)
        - July 29 (Folder 40)
        - August 7 (Folder 41)
        - August 9 (Folder 42)
        - August 13 (Folder 43)
        - September 6 (Folder 44)
        - September 9 (Folder 45)
        - October 17 (Folder 46-47)
        - October 18 (Folder 48)
        - October 20 (Folder 49)
        - October 22 (Folder 50)
        - October 24 (Folder 51)
        - October 27 (Folder 52)
        - November 1 (Folder 53)
        - December 4 (Folder 54)
      - 1920
        - Undated (Folder 55)
        - February 1 (Folder 56)
        - February 17 (Folder 57)
        - February 19 (Folder 58)
        - February 20 (Folder 59)
        - February 27 (Folder 60)
        - March 7 (Folder 61)
        - March 11 (Folder 62)
        - March 28 (Folder 63)
        - March 29 (Folder 64)
        - (ca.), June 13-14 (Folder 65)
        - September 8 (Folder 66)
        - September 9 (Folder 67)
        - September 10 (Folder 68)
        - September 11 (Folder 69)
        - October 1 (Folder 70)
        - October 10 (Folder 71)
        - November 6 (Folder 72)
      - 1921
        - March 3 (Folder 73)
        - March 21 (Folder 74)
        - March 28-29 (Folder 75)
        - April 6 (Folder 76)
        - April 30 (Folder 77)
        - June 5 (Folder 78)
        - June 18 (Folder 79)
        - July 3 (Folder 80)
        - July 28 (Folder 81)
        - July 30 (Folder 82)
        - August 16 (Folder 83)
        - October 9 (Folder 84)
        - October 31 (Folder 85)
        - December 7 (Folder 86)
        - December 26 (Folder 87)
      - 1922
        - January 12 (Box 4, Folder 1)
        - January 16 (Folder 2)
        - January 23 (Folder 3-4)
        - February (day unknown) (Folder 5)
        - February 10 (Folder 6)
        - February 22 (Folder 7)
        - April 4 (Folder 8)
        - April 19 (Folder 9)
        - November 25 (Folder 10-11)
        - December 13 (Folder 12)
        - December 15 (Folder 13-14)
        - December 21 (Folder 15)
      - 1923 March 5-6 (Folder 16)
    - Leon Trotsky to others
      - Anisimov, Nikolai, 1918 November 4 (Folder 17)
      - Arzamas (R.S.F.S.R.) Revoliutsionnyi Voennyi Sovet, 1918 August 17 (Folder 18)
      - Astrakhan' (R.S.F.S.R.) Revoliutsionnyi Voennyi Sovet, 1919 January 26 (Folder 19)
      - Bonch-Bruevich, Mikhail, 1918 August 21 (Folder 20)
      - Chicherin, Georgii
        - 1918 January 31 (Folder 21)
        - 1920 June 4 (Folder 22)
      - Czernin von und zu Chudenitz, Ottokar, Graf, 1918 January 26 (Folder 23)
      - Fotieva, Lidiia, 1921 December 28 (Folder 24)
      - Glazman, Mikhail, 1924 July 26 (Folder 25)
      - Gorbunov, Nikolai, 1922 October 20 (Folder 26)
      - Hoffmann, Max, 1918 February 2 (Folder 27)
      - Kamenev, Lev, 1919 May 9 (Folder 28)
      - Kamenev, Sergei, 1919 September 6 (Folder 29)
      - Kerzhentsev, Platon, 1921 October 4 (Folder 30)
      - Kozlov (Tambovskaia oblast', R.S.F.S.R.) Revoliutsionnyi Voennyi Sovet, 1919 May 23 (Folder 31)
      - Krasin, Leonid
        - 1920 October 16 (Folder 32)
        - 1921 October 4 (Folder 33)
      - Krasnoshchekov, Aleksandr, 1921 March 19 (Folder 34)
      - Krestinskii, Nikolai, 1920
        - March 2 (Folder 35)
        - November 15 (Folder 36)
      - Kuz'min, N. N., (day unknown), 1918 January (Folder 37)
      - Ordzhonikidze, Grigorii, 1920
        - May 27 (Folder 38)
        - June 3 (Folder 39)
      - Petrogradskii Voennyi Okrug. Revoliutsionnyi Voennyi Sovet, 1921 November 28 (Folder 40)
      - Rakovskii, Khristian, 1919 April 18 (Folder 41)
      - Rossiiskaia Kommunisticheskaia Partiia (bol'shevikov) Moskovskii Komitet, 1920 May 2 (Folder 42)
      - Rossiiskaia Kommunisticheskaia Partiia (bol'shevikov) Prezidium, 1921 March 10 (Folder 43)
      - Rossiiskaia Kommunisticheskaia Partiia (bol'shevikov) Tsentral'nyi Komitet. See TSK RKP(b)
      - Russian S.F.S.R. Komissiia po Borbe s Banditizmom, 1921 March 19 (Folder 44-45)
      - Russian S.F.S.R. Narodnyi Komissariat po Voennym i Morskim Delam, (day unknown), 1918 January (Folder 46)
      - Russian S.F.S.R. Raboche-Krestianskaia Krasnaia Armiia. Armiia, 7-ia, 1919 October 27 (Folder 47)
      - Russian S.F.S.R. Raboche-Krestianskaia Krasnaia Armiia. Konnaia Armiia, 1-ia, 1920 October 24 (Folder 48)
      - Russian S.F.S.R. Sovet Truda i Oborony
        - 1919
          - January 4 (Folder 49)
          - June 26 (Folder 50)
        - 1922 August 23 (Folder 51)
      - Saks, Sergei, 1919 January 3 (Folder 52)
      - Semashko, Nikolai, 1920 April 29 (Folder 53)
      - Sklianskii, Efraim
        - 1919
          - May 7 (Folder 54)
          - May 13 (Folder 55)
          - May 16 (Folder 56)
          - May 24 (Folder 57)
          - June 1 (Folder 58)
          - June 7 (Folder 59)
          - October 17 (Folder 60)
        - 1920 May 10 (Folder 61)
        - 1921 February 21 (Folder 62)
      - Smilga, Ivan
        - 1919 October 10 (Folder 63)
        - 1920 February 5 (Folder 64)
      - Smirnov, Ivan, 1920
        - January 13 (Folder 65)
        - February 18 (Folder 66)
      - Stalin, Joseph
        - 1919
          - March 21 (Folder 67)
          - March 22 (Folder 68)
          - March 23 (Folder 69)
          - March 24 (Folder 70-71)
        - 1920
          - (ca.), February 3-4 (Folder 72)
          - February 4 (Folder 73)
        - 1923 April 18 (Folder 74)
      - Sverdlov, Iakov
        - 1918
          - November 1 (Folder 75)
          - November 4 (Folder 76)
          - November 24 (Folder 77)
        - 1919 January 11 (Folder 78)
      - TSK RKP(b)
        - 1918 December 25 (Folder 79)
        - 1919
          - (ca.), March 25-31 (Folder 80)
          - April 5 (Folder 81)
          - May 1 (Folder 82-83)
          - May 3 (Folder 84)
          - May 17 (Folder 85)
          - June 1 (Folder 86)
          - June 5 (Folder 87-89)
          - July 11 (Folder 90)
          - July 14 (Folder 91)
          - July 29 (Folder 92)
          - August 5 (Folder 93)
          - August 7 (Folder 94)
          - August 11 (Folder 95)
          - September 20 (Folder 96)
        - 1920
          - February 17 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
          - February 18 (Folder 4)
          - May 9 (Folder 5)
          - May 10 (Folder 6-7)
          - May 11 (Folder 8)
          - September 9 (Folder 9)
          - December 25 (Folder 10)
        - 1921 August 7 (Folder 11)
        - 1922 June 2 (Folder 12)
        - 1923
          - January 20 (Folder 13)
          - January 25 (Folder 14)
          - February 22 (Folder 15)
          - March 28 (Folder 16)
          - April 16 (Folder 17)
          - April 17 (Folder 18)
          - June 15 (Folder 19)
      - TSK RKP(b) Politbiuro
        - 1919 March 17 (Folder 20)
        - 1920
          - April 17 (Folder 21)
          - July 8 (Folder 22)
          - July 12 (Folder 23)
          - September 2 (Folder 24)
          - November 2 (Folder 25)
        - 1921
          - October 4 (Folder 26)
          - December 3 (Folder 27)
        - 1922
          - January 29 (Folder 28)
          - February 9 (Folder 29)
          - February 10 (Folder 30)
          - March 11 (Folder 31)
          - April 10 (Folder 32)
        - 1923
          - January 15 (Folder 33)
          - February 13 (Folder 34)
          - June 16 (Folder 35)
      - Tsiurupa, Aleksandr, 1920 April 29 (Folder 36)
      - Zinov'ev, Grigorii
        - 1920 January 28 (Folder 37)
        - 1922
          - November 22 (Folder 38)
          - November 23 (Folder 39)
          - November 24 (Folder 40)
    - Others to Leon Trotsky
      - Aralov, Semen, 1918
        - November 8 (Folder 41)
        - December 15 (Folder 42)
      - Berens, Konstantin, 1920 May 27 (Folder 43)
      - Bogdanov, Petr, 1921 November 20 (Folder 44)
      - Bonch-Bruevich, Mikhail, 1918 August 22 (Folder 45)
      - Briukhanov, Nikolai, 1920 February 20 (Folder 46)
      - Chicherin, Georgii, 1919
        - October 22 (Folder 47-48)
        - October 25 (Folder 49)
        - October 26 (Folder 50)
        - October 27 (Folder 51)
        - (ca.), October 29-30 (Folder 52)
        - October 30 (Folder 53)
      - Dzevaltovskii, I. L., 1919 June 24 (Folder 54)
      - Fotieva, Lidiia
        - 1920 February 28 (Folder 55)
        - 1922 May 22 (Folder 56)
      - Frunze, Mikhail, 1920
        - October 15 (Folder 57)
        - October 26 (Folder 58)
        - December 17 (Folder 59)
        - December 19 (Folder 60)
      - Gorbunov, Nikolai
        - 1921 March 2 (Folder 61)
        - 1922 October 19 (Folder 62)
      - Kobozev, Petr, 1918 August 12 (Folder 63)
      - Kopp, Viktor, 1921 April 7 (Folder 64)
      - Krestinskii, Nikolai, 1920
        - February 17 (Folder 65)
        - February 24 (Folder 66)
        - February 27 (Folder 67)
        - March 2 (Folder 68)
      - Lebedev, Pavel, 1920 June 14 (Folder 69)
      - Matiasevich, Mikhail, 1920 January 10 (Folder 70)
      - Natsarenus, S. P., 1918 August 5 (Folder 71)
      - Nevskii, Vladimir, 1918 November 6 (Folder 72)
      - Okhotin, 1918 July 25 (Folder 73)
      - Ordzhonikidze, Grigorii, 1920 June 2 (Folder 74)
      - Podvoiskii, Nikolai, 1918 August 8 (Folder 75)
      - Preobrazhenskii, Evgenii, 1920 May 10 (Folder 76)
      - Prokop'ev, 1918 April 5 (Folder 77)
      - Samoilo, Aleksandr, 1919 September 30 (Folder 78)